# Sai Srinath Josyula

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sai-srinath-josyula/ || http://www.saisrinathjosyula.com || https://github.com/sjosyul1 || LeetCode 801 N Federal St, App 1048, Chandler, Arizona, 85226. | 602-245-5945 | srinath.5893@gmail.com

### Career Summary:

Software Development professional with 3 years' experience in IT industry. Worked on a product called Finacle for over 1.5 years. Have experience working on Full Stack Development using various frameworks like Django, Core .Net, Spring, JSF. Currently, working on developing applications using various frameworks like Spark, MapReduce, Hive, Kafka, Spring, HBase using Java, Scala and Python as programming languages.

#### **Education:**

Master's in Information Technology Arizona State University, AZ. Jan 2017- Dec 2018

CGPA: 4/4

#### Related Coursework:

Analyzing Big Data, Advance Data Analytics, Cloud Computing, Advanced SQL Techniques, System Administration of Unix, Software Engineering, Networking, Algorithms and Data Structures.

#### Skills and Abilities:

Languages: Java, Python, Scala, SQL, C, Bash Script.

Web Technologies: HTML, XML, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, Bootstrap, CSS, JSON, Django, JSP, JSF, Core .Net

Big Data: Spark, MapReduce, Kafka, HBase, Hive, Oozie

Others: Jenkins, XLR, Docker, AWS, Google Cloud, Maven, Kubernetes, Event Engine

#### Masters Projects:

- Analyzed Big data on cloud. Main aim of the project was to find duplication of questions from Quora question pairs. I have
  Used Scala for analyzing data and created Spark clusters on AWS. Data Visualization was done using Amazon Quick Sight
  and Tableau.
- Twitter-Review Analysis: Main aim is to provide review analysis of place, food, events etc. through charts. Used Django to provide user interface. Deployed application on Google App Engine, used BigQuery to store Tweets. Google Data Studio to Visualize data. Technologies: Python, Django, Google App Engine, BigQuery, Google Data Studio.
- SpamHam Analysis: Main aim of the project was if an email is spam or ham using Spark ML techniques. Built ML pipeline using Spark libraries. Technologies used are Spark, Scala, Spark ML
- Built a Meetup portal for ASU polytechnic campus using which students and faculty can organize meetings and share their knowledge. Technologies used JAVA, JDBC, Servlets, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Built a fully functional portal for Photo-voltaic Module certification using Python, Django framework. Used MSSQL as database and implemented Stored procedures, Cursors, Triggers, Views, Dynamic SQL.

#### Work Experience: (Software Engineer)

# Full Time and Internship: Infosys and EdgeVerve:

Apr 2015 - Dec 2016

- Interned in Infosys, Mysore for 5 months on Java, Database Management, Software Engineering, HTML5, CSS3, Java Scripting and Finacle. Completed a Full Stack Web Development project as a part of the Internship.
- Part of Edge Verve, Finacle. It is a banking product developed by Infosys. My work involved development of Finacle Treasury enhancements, moving configuration of app sever to database which enabled FT manager.
- Support of custodian account for securities Buy/Sell, Repo and Equity/MF deals and quick setup which automates the setup of various screens like scheme details, swift messages.

## INTERNSHIP (Project): Edgenuity, Scottsdale

**Sep 2018 – Dec 2018** 

• Developed a software which can create a development environment for Edgenuity employees. User can login and self-configure the software's required for his work and monitor the progress on the dashboard. Languages: C #, Shell Scripting, JS, Bootstrap, Database.

#### **Full Time: Impetus( client Amex):**

Jan 2019- Present

- Part of Batch processing team which primarily works on processing huge chunks of data by writing complex MapReduce, Spark codes using Java, Scala and Python as programming languages.
- Extract data from source Hive tables and run drool rules and load them to HBase tables. Have developed shell scripts which can archive the batch data. Have Developed Oozie scripts to schedule jobs.
- Developed a standalone java application which can read data from Hive and HBase table and push them to Kafka in required format. Application is triggered using a job scheduler called Event Engine. Developed Kafka consumer to consume and test.
- Expertise in using build tools like Jenkins, Maven. I'm using XLR to control the entire Software Life Cycle.
- Perform Unit Test, Integration Test, Regression test on developed code and Applications.
- Currently developing a web portal using React JS to simulate the behavior of batch logic for business team. Expertise in deploying Kafka topics, Application code, Event engine to various environments using DTC profiles, Jenkins and XLR.